(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T02:14:25.930535",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
お宝探しに大海原いざ出航だ！
Setting sail across the ocean to find treasure!
身も心もぴょんぴょんワクワク有頂天！
Body and soul bounding and thrilling with excitement!
水平線向こう側新天地待っててね
A new world awaits beyond the horizon,
運命なんか飛び越えてその先へさあ
so let's leap past destiny and head beyond!
リアリティ×ファンタジー二つの狭間へ
To the interstice of reality and fantasy,
夢歌え声高く一緒にさあ
let's sing our dreams aloud together!
まだ見えない世界へと君を連れてくよ
I'll take you to a world we've never seen,
みんながつながる物語さあ始まるよ！
a connected story is about to begin!
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
みんなの志抱き挑め騎士団集合！
Knights assemble, embracing everyone's ambitions!
胸に宿る太陽風を切ってさらに輝け！
Cut through the solar wind in your heart and shine brighter!
メイスと夢晴天に掲げたら突撃だ
Raise your mace and dreams to the clear sky and charge!
妖精達この旅路見守って
Fairies, watch over this journey.
さあ
Now,
リアリティ×ファンタジー二つの狭間へ
to the interstice of reality and fantasy,
帆を上げて迎えユートピアへさあ
raise your sails and welcome utopia!
それぞれのの世界から嵒根を越えたらば
Crossing over the bedrock from our respective worlds,
みんながつながる物語さあ始まるよ！
a connected story is about to begin!
明るく陽気に荒波乗り越えて
Cheerfully riding over rough waves,
holo! live!
Hololive!
愛嬌解放ぬさ耳澄まして
Releasing our charm, listen closely,
holo! live!
Hololive!
騎士道と誇り胸に刻んだら
Engraving chivalry and pride in our hearts,
holo! live!
Hololive!
神話に伝わる神秘な囁き
A mysterious whisper passed down in myth,
holo! live!
Hololive!
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
さあリアリティ×ファンタジー二つの狭間へ
Now, to the interstice of reality and fantasy,
夢歌え声高く一緒にさあ
let's sing our dreams aloud together!
まだ見えない世界へと君を連れてくよ
I'll take you to a world we've never seen,
準備はほら出来たよルートも決まったよ
prep is ready, the route is decided too,
みんながつながる物語さあ始まるよ！
a connected story is about to begin!
冒険！出発！さあ！
Adventure! Departure! Now!
挑戦！開始！さあ！
Challenge! Start! Now!
明るく陽気に荒波乗り越えて
Cheerfully riding over rough waves,
holo! live!
Hololive!
愛嬌解放ぬさ耳澄まして
Releasing our charm, listen closely,
holo! live!
Hololive!
騎士道と誇り胸に刻んだら
Engraving chivalry and pride in our hearts,
holo! live!
Hololive!
神話に伝わる神秘な囁き
A mysterious whisper passed down in myth,
holo! live!
Hololive!
リアリティ×ファンタジー二つの狭間へ
To the interstice of reality and fantasy,
夢歌え声高く一緒にさあ
let's sing our dreams aloud together!
まだ見えない世界へと君を連れてくよ
I'll take you to a world we've never seen,
準備はほら出来たよルートも決まったよ
prep is ready, the route is decided too,
みんながつながる物語さあ始まるよ！
a connected story is about to begin!
まだ見えない世界へと君を連れてくよ
I'll take you to a world we've never seen,
準備はほら出来たよルートも決まったよ
prep is ready, the route is decided too,
みんながつながる物語さあ始まるよ！
a connected story is about to begin!
はい！
Yes!
始まりましたー！
We're starting!
ホロライブ3期生5周年ライブ！
Hololive 3rd Generation 5th Anniversary Live!
「スクエア・オブ・マジック！」
"Square of Magic!"
ハッシュタグは3期生5周年ライブになりますので、ぜひつけてたくさんポストしてください！
The hashtag is 3rd Gen 5th Anniversary Live, so please post a lot!
ということで、一通り自己紹介していきましょうか、じゃあぺこちゃん！
So, let's go around and introduce ourselves, starting with Peko-chan!
ぺこぺこぺこぺこぺこー！
Peko-peko-peko-peko-peko!
回ってまーす！
We're spinning around!
5周年になり新たなうさぎになった、ホロライブ3期生のうさだぺこら！
Usada Pekora of Hololive 3rd Gen, a brand new rabbit for our 5th anniversary!
とと、と、とって感じ！
Something like that!
こんぬい！ホロライブ3期生の不破エルフェ……
Konnui! Shiranui Flar... of Hololive 3rd Gen...
えーっと、新たなエルフそんになったしらぬいふえりです！よろしくお願いします！
Um, I'm Shiranui Flare, an upgraded elf! Nice to meet you!
あい、えー、まする、まする！えっと、豪快や優雅な、えっと……
Aye, um, brave and elegant, um...
5周年で優雅になったノエルではない！
Not Noel who became elegant for the 5th anniversary!
魔法も使っちゃう白銀ノエルかもしれないのと、と、何？何だって？
Maybe Shirogane Noel who also uses magic? Wait, what? What's that?
あーい！えー、ホロライブ3期生宝鐘海賊団船長の、えー、なんか5周年になったけど一生老けない宝鐘マリンでーす！
I'm Houshou Marine, captain of the Houshou Pirate Crew of Hololive 3rd Gen, who somehow won't age a day!
せーの、われらの、ホロライブファンタジー！
Ready, go! Our Hololive Fantasy!
ということでね！
So that's right!
今回、
This time,
Square of Magicということでステージも映像に囲まれた空間でね、やらさていただいております！
With "Square of Magic," our stage is surrounded by visuals!
すごい！
Amazing!
すごいねこのステージ、今回映像がね、かなりこってるのでね、ぜひ楽しみにしていてほしいです！
This stage is incredible! The visuals are really elaborate, so please look forward to it!
お願いします！
Please do!
はい、いっぱい見てください！
Yes, please watch plenty!
で、もうね5周年ってことで、もうまじ早くない？5年？
And since it's already the 5th anniversary, isn't it super fast? 5 years?
いやー、まだね、
Man, still...
ねぇ、もう同期にいるってことだもんね？
Right, being with our gen-mates and all?
じゃ、5年ちょっとやってきて、こう振り返ってみます？じゃぺこらちゃんどうぞ。
So having done this for over 5 years, let's look back, shall we? Pekora-chan, go ahead.
そうですね。
Let's see...
そういう長かったよ
It was long, you know.
いや、でも短かったよ。
No, but it was short.
配信前にやれるよ、それ。
You can do that before the stream.
いやでも今ちょうど始まって、今これぐらいだ。
Well, but it just started, we're about this far.
でさ、でさ、だから3期生でよかったなって思う。5年目。6年目もやらぴこま！
And so, I feel so glad to be in the 3rd Gen. 5th year. Let's do 6 years too!
やろやろポストでね！はい！
Let's do post-it! Yeah!
じゃあフレアちゃん。
Now, Flare-chan.
長かったよう、
It was long,
で、でもあっという間だった！同期生の絆、これからも あるよね？
But, but it went by in a flash! Our 3rd Gen bond will keep going from now on too, right?
5年といったら小学生が1年生から5年生になるという、そういう中途半端でしょ？
Saying 5 years is like an elementary student going from 1st to 5th grade, kinda halfway, right?
でも、あと来年6年、頑張るぞという気持ち、あるよね？
But you feel like you'll work hard for the 6th year next year too, right?
マリンは？3期生5年か…長かったような、短かった5年間。
How about Marine? 5 years of 3rd Gen... A 5 years that felt long yet short.
ぺこらちゃん結婚したよね？結婚したこともありました。
Pekora-chan got married, right? There was a time you got married too.
そしてフレアちゃん結婚したよね？したこともありました。
And Flare-chan got married, right? There was a time you did too.
ノエルと、とも子作りしたね、それは。子作り確か父だ。
And Noel and I made a child, that's right. Child-making was definitely dad.
って感じで色々ありましたが、みんな仲良くやっていこう！ということで、
So various things happened, but let's all get along well! With that said,
3期生6年目も頑張っていきますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
We'll keep doing our best in our 6th year as 3rd Gen, so please cheer us on!
まだまだライブはこれからですよ！こんなこと喋ってる場合じゃない！次行っちゃいましょう！
The live is just getting started! This is no time to be chatting like this! Let's move on to the next!
では準備するので、一旦はけましょうか。お、出てきた！お城だ！
Well, we'll prep, so let's head off stage for a moment. Oh, it appeared! A castle!
chu chu yeah! 青空のラプソディ
Chu chu yeah! Aozora no Rhapsody
chu chu yeah! please me!
あんなこと言えばすんなり間違い探し
Saying things like that easily finds mistakes
自分のことにダラダラ怠惰な契約
A lazy, dragging contract with myself
どうしてと突然逃げ出したっていいでしょ
It's fine to suddenly run away crying 'Why?' right?
だけどなんだか気まぐれ戻りになりそんな気分になっちゃって
But somehow, whimsically turning back, ending up in that kind of mood
始まりはそんな風で
The beginning is just like that
つまりはらしくないよで
In short, it doesn't seem like me
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら声が聞こえるよさあ
But now, open the door, look, you can hear voices, come on!
行こう　どこへでも
Let's go, anywhere at all!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to become your wings!
どんな試練も怖くない　その魔法があるからさ
No trials are scary because you have that magic!
いつかここで初めて出会えた世界に
Someday, in this world where we first met,
また涙を拭こう　そしてその瞬間結ばれるよ
I'll wipe my tears again, and at that moment we'll be bound together
しずはぐなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない
Even gentle communication is totally fine
起きてから返事すんなら
If you reply after waking up
chu chu yeah! 膝中!
Chu chu yeah! Knee-chu!
あーどうしてまた素直になれなくて自分のことでずるるずるずる引きずり
Ah, why can't I be honest again, dragging my own matters along endlessly
気圧そのままスピード上げていこう
Let's keep the air pressure and boost our speed!
だけどなんだか嘘から元通りになり
But somehow going back to normal from a lie
いつか思い出しゃって一人でいても癒されない
Someday recalling it, even being alone isn't healed
誰にも頼らなくてもいい
It's fine not to rely on anyone
でも扉の向こう騒がしい声が切りたいよ今
But the noisy voices beyond the door want to cut in right now!
行こう　どこへでも
Let's go, anywhere at all!
僕は君を背中に乗せて空を舞うよ
I'll carry you on my back and dance through the sky!
いつか心が離れてもその時は笑ってて
Even if our hearts drift apart someday, please smile at that time
誰も見たことのない世界に青空のラプソディ
To a world no one has ever seen, Aozora no Rhapsody
世代をまぜてほかなんだっていいぜ
Mixing generations, anything is fine!
chu chu yeah! please me!
Chu-chu-yeah! Please me!
chu chu yeah! without you!
Chu-chu-yeah! Without you!
あー、なんてことだ 些細な過ちだ
Ah, what a thing, it's a trivial mistake
自分のことにタラッタラッタラ手焼く
Struggling with my own affairs, tra-la-la-la
どうして突然? 逃げ切ったっていいでしょ?
Why so suddenly? It's fine to run away, right?
だけどなんだか気まぐれモードになり
But somehow I switch to a fickle mood
そんな気分になっちゃって
Becoming that kind of mood
始まりはそんな風で つまりはらしくないようで
The beginning is like that, in short it seems unlike me
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら 声が聴こえるよ
But now, open the door, look, you can hear the voice
さあ行こう どこででも
Now then, let's go, wherever it may be
僕は君の翼に
I can be your wings
なれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to be
どんな試練も怖くない
No trials are scary
その魔法があるから
Because that magic is there
初めて出会う世界に 花束を贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet to the world we meet for the first time
ただこの瞬間結ばれよ
Just bound together in this moment
僕は君の翼に
I can be your wings
なれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to be
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
No trials are scary because that magic is there
君と出会い世界は木漏れ日に溢れた
Meeting you, the world overflowed with sunlight filtering through trees
ただその瞬間結ばれたよ
We were bound together in that exact moment
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーション? でも別に構わない
Mismatched communication? But it doesn't matter
明日から平和なら!
As long as tomorrow is peaceful!
ほんの小さな切なさを太陽にさらして
Exposing just a small bit of sadness to the sun
わけあったよ、君と
We shared it, you and I
chu chu yeah! いきなビートはじくぼくらは
Chu-chu-yeah! We flick a stylish beat
please me! 手をたたいて
Please me! Clapping our hands
chu chu yeah! ぶげいなリズムですしゃぐふたりは
Chu-chu-yeah! The two of us frolicking to a wild rhythm
without you! とびはねてさ
Without you! Jumping around
息を切らし
Out of breath
without you!
晴る 作詞・作曲:n-buna
[Song: Haru | Lyrics & Music: n-buna]
貴方は風のように 目を閉じては夕暮れ
You are like the wind, closing your eyes at dusk
何を思っているんだろうか 目蓋を開けていた
What are you thinking about? You had your eyelids open
貴方の目はビイドロ 少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
Your eyes are like glass, carrying just a hint of clear skies
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clearer and clearer, flowers bloom, blooming because of the clear skies
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even the rain, once it stops, is a clear sky adorning you
胸を打つ音よ響け 僕ら晴る風
Sound that strikes the heart, resound, we are the clearing wind
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまで遠くまで
Cross over those clouds too, far away, far into the distance
貴方は晴れ模様に 目を閉じては青色
You are in a clear pattern, closing your eyes to blue
何が悲しいのだろうか 目蓋を開けている
What is making you sad? You keep your eyelids open
貴方の目にビイドロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
In your glass-like eyes, there was just a hint of rain now
泣きに泣き、空よ泣け 泣いて雨のせい
Weep and weep, sky weep, weeping because of the rain
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even the incessant rain is clearing above the clouds
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
Sound that beats the earth, resound, we are the spring storm
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠くまで遠くまで
Cross over that sea too, far away, far into the distance
通り雨、草を靡かせ 羊雲、あれも春のせい
Passing shower, swaying the grass, altocumulus clouds, that too is because of spring
風のように、胸に春乗せ 春を待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring in our hearts, waiting for spring
晴れに晴れ、空よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clearer and clearer, sky bloom, blooming because of the clear skies
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even the rain, once it stops, is a clear sky adorning you
胸を打つ音奏で 僕ら晴る風
Playing a sound that strikes the heart, we are the clearing wind
音に聞く晴るの風 さあこの歌よ響け
The clearing wind heard in sound, now let this song resound
貴方は晴れのように 目を閉じては青色
You are like the clear sky, closing your eyes to blue
何が悲しいのだろうか 目蓋を開けている
What is making you sad? You keep your eyelids open
貴方の目にビイドロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
In your glass-like eyes, there was just a hint of rain now
通り雨、草を靡かせ 羊雲、あれも春のせい
Passing shower, swaying the grass, altocumulus clouds, that too is because of spring
風のように、胸に春乗せ 春を待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring in our hearts, waiting for spring
晴れに晴れ、空よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clearer and clearer, sky bloom, blooming because of the clear skies
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even the rain, once it stops, is a clear sky adorning you
胸を打つ音奏で 僕ら晴る風
Playing a sound that strikes the heart, we are the clearing wind
音に聞く晴るの風 さあこの歌よ響け
The clearing wind heard in sound, now let this song resound
泣きに泣き、空よ泣け 泣いて雨のせい
Weep and weep, sky weep, weeping because of the rain
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even the incessant rain is clearing above the clouds
土を打つ音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
Sound that beats the earth, resound, we are the spring storm
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠くまで遠くまで
Cross over that sea too, far away, far into the distance
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴るのせい
Clearer and clearer, flowers bloom, blooming because of the clear skies
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴る
Even the rain, once it stops, is a clear sky adorning you
胸を打つ音奏で 僕ら晴る風
Playing a sound that strikes the heart, we are the clearing wind
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまで遠くまで
Cross over those clouds too, far away, far into the distance
貴方は風のように
You are like the wind,
目を閉じては夕暮れ
closing your eyes at twilight.
何を思っているんだろうか
I wonder what you're thinking about...
目蓋を開いていた
With your eyelids open,
貴方の目はビードロ 少しだけ晴れの匂いがした
your eyes are like glass, with a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom!
晴れに晴れ、空よ裂け
Clear up, oh sky, and tear open!
裂いて春のせい
Tearing open for the sake of spring!
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴れ
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clear skies.
胸を打つ音よ鳴え 僕ら春風
Oh sound that strikes the heart, resonate, we are the spring breeze!
音に聴く晴れの風 さあこの歌よ凪げ
Listen to the sound of the clearing wind! Now, cast this song out!
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて春のせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom, blossom for the sake of spring!
あの雲も越えてゆけ
Go beyond those clouds,
遠くまで遠くまで
far, still far away!
チート、gifted
Cheated, gifted,
荒技、wanted
beat and make 'em wanted.
禁忌、禁じ手、明白な盲点
Block it, stall, obvious blind spots.
反則、異次元、この世の中のものでは無いです
Strange, from another world, not of this world.
無理ゲー、それ聞いてないって
Impossible game, you didn't hear about that?
アイ ライバル口を揃えて ウォー ライバル口を揃えて
Ay, chasing my rival in unison, wow, in unison!
バグで、まぐれ、認めてぜったいマジで
Bug, fluke, admit it for real, seriously!
これお前全部生で見て
See all of this live with your own eyes!
It’s 生身 It’s 生身 yeah yeah yeah yeah
It's genuine, it's genuine, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
実力を発揮し切る前に相手の方がバックれてくらしい
Before I can even show my true strength, the opponent backs off.
上がり切るハードル very happy
Overcoming hurdles, very happy!
相変わらず脱皮してる毎日
Still shedding skin every single day.
誰の七光りもいらないお前のiceより icy
Don't need anyone's borrowed light, icier than your ice.
俺、パッと見できないことばっかりだけど very happy
I'm full of things I can't do at a glance, but very happy!
あ、切れてる…呆れてる周り 恵まれている家族友達
Oh, people are pissed... baffled, yet blessed with family and friends.
もう反則的立ち位置、皆俺に任しとけば良い
Such a foul position, just leave it all to me!
教科書に無い問題集に無い超BADな呪い listen
No textbooks, no question books, a super bad curse—listen!
鏡よ鏡答えちゃって Who’s the best? I’m the best! Oh yeah
Mirror, mirror on the wall, who's the best? I'm the best! Oh yeah!
生身のままで行けるこことまで
In the raw, going as far as I can!
To the next, To the 1番上
To the next, to the very top!
Now singin’
Now singing:
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
Eyday 俺のままで居るだけで超flex
Eyday, just being myself is a super flex.
Eyday 誰も口を挟めない(Don't test)
Eyday, nobody dares to interrupt. (Don't test)
Eyday 俺のままで居るだけで超flex
Eyday, just being myself is a super flex.
Eyday 誰も口を挟ませない(Don't test)
Eyday, nobody can interrupt. (Don't test)
学歴もない 前科もない 余裕でbling-bling
No degree, no criminal record, effortlessly bling-bling.
この存在自体が文化財 な脳みそbling-bling
This existence itself is a cultural asset, a brain full of bling-bling.
高級車は買える免許はない 愛車green green
Can buy a luxury car, no license, my beloved green green car.
全国各地揺らす逸品 このベロがbling-bling
A masterpiece shaking every corner of the country, this tongue is bling-bling.
バレットなら満タン 関西なまり生身のコトダマ
Bullet fully loaded, Kansai dialect, living kotodama.
音楽 幸運 勝利の女神 今宵も三股 bang bang
Music, fortune, goddess of victory, a three-way tie tonight too—bang bang!
漫画みたいなヤカラとマンガまで張り詰めてしまってる漫画
Pushing the limits like a living manga character.
圧倒的力 この頭と口から
Overwhelming power from this head and mouth!
この身体タトゥーは入ってない このツラに傷もついてない
No tattoos on this body, no scars on this face.
繰り返しやらかしてくダメージが イカツイ年輪を刻む皺
Repeated blunders and damage carve rugged wrinkles.
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
俺のままでblingしてbangしてbangする為にbornしてきたニッポン yeh
Born in Japan just to bling, bang, and bang being myself, yeh!
鏡よ鏡答えちゃって Who’s the best? I’m the best! Oh yeah
Mirror, mirror on the wall, who's the best? I'm the best! Oh yeah!
生身のままで行けるこことまで
In the raw, going as far as I can!
To the next, To the 1番上
To the next, to the very top!
Eyday 俺のままで居るだけで超flex
Eyday, just being myself is a super flex.
Eyday 誰も口を挟めない(Don't test)
Eyday, nobody dares to interrupt. (Don't test)
Eyday 俺のままで居るだけで超flex
Eyday, just being myself is a super flex.
Eyday 誰も口を挟ませない(Don't test)
Eyday, nobody can interrupt. (Don't test)
愛嬌＋嫉妬、と、愛と涙で割ったら
Add love and jealousy, and with love and tears if you split it,
世界で一番可愛いモンスター 「少女」が完成
the cutest monster in the world, the "girl" is complete!
眉と目を足して
Add eyebrows and eyes...
目を閉じれば 億千の星
When I close my eyes, a hundred million stars...
一番輝くお前がいる
You're shining the brightest.
初めて一途になれたよ 夜空へ響け愛のうた
For the first time I could be devoted,
resound into the night sky, love song.
大親友の彼女の連れ おいしいパスタ作ったお前
My best friend's girlfriend's acquaintance,
you made delicious pasta.
家庭的な女のタイプの一目惚れ
I fell at first sight
for a domestic-type girl.
大大貧民負けてマジ切れ それ見て笑って楽しいねって
Losing big in Daifugou and getting mad,
you laughed seeing that and said "How fun."
優しい笑顔にまた癒やされて ベタ惚れ
Comforted once more by your gentle smile,
completely infatuated.
嬉しくて嬉しくて柄にもなくスキップして
So happy, so happy,
skipping out of character,
「好きって言ってって」おぼろげな月を見つめる君に釘付け
Captivated by you staring at the hazy moon,
wanting you to say "I love you."
守りたい女って思った初めて
Thinking for the first time,
"She's a woman I want to protect,"
まじめな顔してぎゅっと抱きしめた
with a serious face I held you tight.
全方位美少女
Beautiful girls in every direction!
横から見ても下から見ても知ったから見てもいい女って
Looking from the side, below, or behind,
you're such a fine woman,
止まって
Stop right there!
君は全方位美少女
You're a beauty from all angles!
ねえ止まって
Hey, stop right there!
中身も素性も全部愛して受け取るの
Love and accept everything,
inside and out.
Eyes on you, every time I find out you're so sweet...
Eyes on you, every time
I find out you're so sweet...
アイラインを跳ね上げ 天まで届くまつげ
Winged eyeliner,
eyelashes reaching the heavens.
頬にバラ咲かせて ルージュでその色つけて
Making roses bloom on your cheeks,
coloring them with rouge.
よき人に好換れんが 身なりも分かってます
I know how to dress
to be liked by good people.
美しさも愛嬌も 電話に物を与えます
Beauty and charm
give things to the phone.
遠くなんて一生をかけた一つずつ集めるもの
Faraway things are gathered
one by one over a lifetime.
今も昔も始まって今はちゃんと愛してね
From past to present, it started,
now please love me properly.
横から見ても下から見ても知ったから見てもいい女って
Looking from the side, below, or behind,
you're such a fine woman,
止まって
Stop right there!
君は全方位美少女
You're a beauty from all angles!
ねえ止まって
Hey, stop right there!
中身も素性も全部愛して受け取るの
Love and accept everything,
inside and out.
Eyes on you, every time I find out you're so sweet...
Eyes on you, every time
I find out you're so sweet...
君は全方位美少女
You're a beauty from all angles!
そろりそろり...
Slowly, slowly...
いいよ！
That's great!
横から見て、下から見て、上から見て...
Look from the side, look from below,
look from above...
みんな喋ってみたら違ったみたいな
Everyone sounded different
when they tried talking.
皆さん、この3期生ライブ、いかがですか？
Everyone, how do you like
this 3rd Gen Live?
こちらね、マリンが結構ね、全体の曲とか考えたんですけれど
Marine thought quite a bit about
the overall song selection...
ソロ曲なんだけど、やっぱ3期生全員いる感じは出したくて
It's a solo song, but I wanted
to give the feeling of all 3rd Gen...
全体的に3期生が常にどっかしら映り込むような感じになるようにこだわってやりました
We made sure 3rd Gen members constantly
appear somewhere throughout.
天才です！
You're a genius!
みこちが抜け出して見に来てくれてる
Mikochi snuck out
to come watch us!
よっ！
Yo!
このあともね、みんなの声に合った楽しい演出になっているので楽しみにしていてください
From here on, too, we have fun productions
suited to everyone's voices!
デュエット曲になります！
It's going to be a duet song!
マリりと、も...?
Mariri and Mo...?
デュエット曲で誰と誰がどんな歌をううのか、他のメンバーが現れることがあるのかお楽しみに！
Look forward to who sings what kind of duet song,
and if other members appear!
皆さん、立ち位置に付いて！
Everyone, get to your positions!
君を泣かすからだから一緒には入れないな
I make you cry,
so we can't be together after all.
君を泣かすから早く忘れてほしいんだ
I make you cry,
so I want you to forget me quickly.
人間だからね たまには違うものも食べたいね
We're human, after all,
sometimes we want to eat something different too.
君を泣かすから そう君を泣かすから
I make you cry,
yes, I make you cry.
でも味けないないないないんだよね 会いたい会いたい会いたいんだよね
But it's so dull, isn't it?
I want to see you so bad.
大体曖昧なんだよね 愛の存在証明なんて
They're mostly just vague things like proof that love exists.
君が教えてくれないか
Won't you teach me?
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Like spending dozens of nights without ever finding...
知ってるを並べてみて
Just lining up all the "I know"s.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Spending dozens of nights without ever finding...
最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full course.
君を泣かすから きっと一生は無理だよね
I'll make you cry, so forever is surely impossible, right?
君を泣かすから 胸がとても痛いんだ
I'll make you cry, so my chest aches so deeply.
人間だからね たまには分かり合えなくなって
We're human after all, sometimes unable to understand each other.
君を泣かすから また君を泣かすから
I'll make you cry, I'll make you cry again.
でも自信がないないないないないよね
But I've got no confidence at all...
変わりたくないないないないよね
I don't want to change at all...
なんて勝手だね
How selfish of me.
大体曖昧だったよね 愛の存在証明なんて
They were mostly just vague things like proof that love exists.
君がそこにいるのにね
Even though you're right there.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Like spending hundreds of nights without ever finding...
知ってるを並べてみて
Just lining up all the "I know"s.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full course of spending hundreds of nights...
離れないで 傍に居てくれたのは 結局君一人だったよね
In the end, the only one who didn't leave and stayed by my side was you.
涙のスパイスは 君の胸に残ってしまうんだろうけど
Though the spice of tears will likely remain in your chest...
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような
Like spending thousands of nights without ever finding...
知ってるを並べるから
I'll line up all the "I know"s.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られぬような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full course of spending thousands of nights...
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような
Like spending tens of thousands of nights without ever forgetting...
知ってるを並べるから
I'll line up all the "I know"s.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れぬような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
Give me the ultimate full course of spending tens of thousands of nights without forgetting...
光る雲を突き抜け Fly Away
Piercing the shining clouds, I fly away!
からだじゅうに 広がるパノラマ
A panorama spreads across my body.
顔を蹴られた地球が怒って 火山を爆発させる
The Earth, kicked in the face, gets angry and makes volcanoes explode!
溶けた氷の中に
Within the melted ice...
恐竜がいたら 玉乗り仕込みたいね
If there's a dinosaur, I want to teach it to balance on a ball!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
何が起きても気分は へのへのかっぱ
No matter what happens, I feel totally carefree!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
胸がパチパチするほど 騒ぐ元気玉
My Genki-Dama roars as my heart pounds!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
頭カラッポの方が 夢詰め込める
An empty head is better for stuffing with dreams!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
笑顔ウルトラZで 今日もアイアイアイ...
With an ultra-Z smile, today is also i-yai-yai...
空を急降下 Jet Coaster
Diving through the sky on a roller coaster,
落ちてゆくよ パニックの楽園へ
I fall into a paradise of panic!
景色逆さまになると 愉しさは
The scenery turns upside-down and I cheer up,
山さえお尻に見える
'cause the mountains even look like butts!
悩む時間はないよ
There's no time for worrying,
どこかに潜む 「びっくり！」 に逢いたいから
'cause there's a surprise hidden somewhere, and I wanna find it!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
頭カラッポの方が 夢詰め込める
An empty head is better for stuffing with dreams!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
笑顔ウルトラZで 今日もアイアイアイ...
With an ultra-Z smile, today is also i-yai-yai...
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
何が起きても気分は へのへのかっぱ
No matter what happens, I feel totally carefree!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
胸がパチパチするほど 騒ぐ元気玉…Sparking!
My Genki-Dama roars as my heart pounds... Sparking!
光る雲を突き抜け fly away
Piercing the shining clouds, I fly away
からだじゅうに広がるパノラマ
While a panorama spreads through my body.
顔を蹴られた地球が怒って
Kicked in the face, the earth gets angry
火山を爆発させる
and makes a volcano explode!
溶けた北極の中に
Within the melted polar ice,
恐竜がいたら玉乗り仕込みたいね
if there's a dinosaur, I want to train it!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
何が起きてても気分はへのへのカッパ
No matter what happens, I feel like it's no big deal!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
胸がパチパチするほど
Just as loudly as my heart pounds,
騒ぐ元気玉…sparking!
the Genki-Dama roars... Sparking!
空を急降下 jet coaster
Diving through the sky on a roller coaster,
落ちていくよパニックの楽園へ
I fall into a paradise of panic!
景色逆さまになると愉快さ
The scenery turns upside-down and I cheer up,
山さえお尻に見える
'cause the mountains even look like butts!
悩む時間はないよ
There's no time for worrying,
どこかに潜む「ビックリ!」に逢いたいから
'cause there's a surprise hidden somewhere!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
頭カラッポの方が夢詰め込める
I'd rather have my head empty to fill it with dreams!
笑顔ウルトラZで今日もアイアイアイアイ…
With a smile that's ultra-Z, even today is ai-yai-yai...
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
何が起きてても気分はへのへのカッパ
No matter what happens, I feel like it's no big deal!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
胸がパチパチするほど
Just as loudly as my heart pounds,
騒ぐ元気玉…sparking!
the Genki-Dama roars... Sparking!
CHA-LA HEAD-CHA-LA
胸がパチパチするほど
Just as loudly as my heart pounds,
騒ぐ元気玉…sparking!
the Genki-Dama roars... Sparking!
吾愛イ尓 酔いが覚めない oh, i need you 恋が覚めない
Wo aini, my drunkenness won't fade, oh I need you, my love won't fade.
お生憎様の慣れ果て察して 無問題 破滅してみせて
Pity the pathetic state you've become, no problem, try getting ruined.
hold me tight トラウマの味 猛反対 お手お座りでおハイ♡ 報酬
Hold me tight, the taste of trauma, strongly opposed, sit, give your paw, yes, reward.
喉の奥がチクンチクン
The back of my throat tingles,
僕はドクンドクン
my heart beats thump thump.
心拍で孤独消してみてよ
Show me you can erase my solitude with your heartbeat.
愛も恋も独裁して 僕を独占して
Dictate both love and romance, monopolize me,
このまま中毒になるまでチュしよう
kiss me until we're addicted just like this.
そして get get get on! get get get on! get on chu!
And then, get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
熱く溶けるくらいに溢れた気持ちがたまらないでしょ?
Feelings overflowing so much it melts with heat, can't help it, right?
吾愛イ尓 無問題 get get get on chu!
Wo aini, moumantai, get get get on chu!
ポン・チー・カン 勝負はいつもトンチンカン
Pon, chi, kan, the match is always nonsense,
僕に言わせりゃちんぷんかんぷんだ 最後はロンでしょ?
if you ask me, it's gibberish, in the end it's ron, right?
もう何回? 殺されればいい oh, one night
How many times do I have to be killed? Oh, one night,
忘れられない終わりないでトキメキ偏愛♡予習
unforgettable, unending, throbbing biased love preview.
喉の奥がチクンチクン 僕はドクンドクン
The back of my throat tingles, my heart beats thump thump,
心臓ごと引きずり出してみてよ
drag out my heart and show it to me.
気持ちいいね 面倒くさいけど やっぱ照れ臭いけど
It feels good, even though it's troublesome, even though it's embarrassing,
死ぬまで忘れられないチュしよう
let's kiss so we can't forget until we die.
いかれた街はゾンビで溢れる 君は僕に恋している
The crazy town is overflowing with zombies, you are in love with me,
ときめく胸に繋がるロープを引けよ
pull the rope connected to your throbbing chest.
いくよ bet bet bet on!
Here we go, bet bet bet on!
本気で狂えるくらいの鬱屈さが美しいんでしょ?
The gloomy melancholy of going genuinely crazy is beautiful, isn't it?
get get get on! get get get on! get on chu!
せーの ポン・チー・カン 終わりない get get get on chu!
Ready, pon, chi, kan, it won't end, get get get on chu!
ほらね 吾愛イ尓 無問題 get get get on chu!
See, wo aini, moumantai, get get get on chu!
ドンチーカン 勝負はいつもドンチーカン
Don, chi, kan, the match is always don, chi, kan,
僕に言わせりゃちんちんかん 分厚いサイコーをロンでしょ?
if you ask me, it's chinchinkan, the thickest saikou is ron, right?
もうなんか やられればいい 終わない 忘れられない 終わない
Or rather, getting hurt is fine, won't end, unforgettable, won't end,
でドキメキ変愛♡よしゅう
and throbbing strange love preparation.
気持ちいいね めんどくさいけど やっぱてれくさいけど
It feels good, even though it's troublesome, even though it's embarrassing,
死ぬまではすれられないチュしよう
let's kiss so we can't forget until we die.
いかれた街はゾンビで溢れる 君は僕に恋している
The crazy town is overflowing with zombies, you are in love with me,
ときめく胸に繋がるロープをひけよ
pull the rope connected to your throbbing chest.
いくよ get get get on!
Here we go, get get get on!
本気で狂えるくらいの鬱屈さが美しいんでしょ?
The gloomy melancholy of going genuinely crazy is beautiful, isn't it?
get get get on! get get get on! get on chu!
せーの ポン・チー・カン 終わりない get get get on chu!
Ready, pon, chi, kan, it won't end, get get get on chu!
ほらね 吾愛イ尓 無問題 get get get on chu!
See, wo aini, moumantai, get get get on chu!
気持ちいいけど めんどくさいけど
It feels good, even though it's troublesome,
やっぱてれくさいけど 死ぬまではすれられないチュしよう
even though it's embarrassing, let's kiss so we can't forget until we die.
いかれた街はゾンビで溢れる 君は僕に恋している
The crazy town is overflowing with zombies, you are in love with me,
ときめく胸に繋がるロープをひけよ
pull the rope connected to your throbbing chest.
get get get on! get get get on! get on chu!
get get get on! get get get get on chu!
マジで狂えるくらいの鬱屈さが
The gloomy melancholy of going genuinely crazy
美しいんでしょ?
is beautiful, isn't it?
素敵でしょ ゲキゲキロケロゲロチュウ
It's wonderful, geki geki rokeroge rochu!
ゲキゲキロケロゲロチュウ せーの ポン・チー・カン
Geki geki rokeroge rochu, ready, pon, chi, kan,
終わりない
it won't end,
ゲキゲキロケロゲロチュウ
geki geki rokeroge rochu!
ほらね 吾愛イ尓 無問題
See, wo aini, moumantai,
ゲキゲキロケロゲロチュウ
geki geki rokeroge rochu!
アイパイダンスホール 今日はポレロ
IPai Dance Hall, today is bolero,
とろけってしょうね 甘酸っぱレモン
melting away, sweet and sour lemon,
キュン倍 人口いっぱい満杯
heart-pounding times, population overflowing and full.
オーブンタースタはモレモレ
Oven toasters are leaking out,
よおかわりはアンコール未来ね
seconds are an encore for the future.
終わらないラブラブドールがすべて
Endless loveable dolls are everything.
459226535のパイだって
It's a 459226535 pie,
割り切れない気持ち抱えてるよ
carrying feelings that can't be divided.
ロボットもゲンジンもエンジンも
Hoping robots, cavemen, and engines
エンジン組んで仲良くやれたらとか
could team up and get along—
割り切れない命 一生サイズのヘブン
an undivided life, a lifetime-sized heaven!
今夜はいいんじゃない? ほら、追え 追え 追え
Isn't tonight fine? Come on, chase, chase, chase!
踊ればいいんじゃない? ほら、ふり ふり ふられれば急転直下
Wouldn't it be fine to dance? Swing and turn around!
少女 雷電が 現世を制す
Maiden Raiden dominating the mortal world!
朝晩 団々 散々さ
Morning and night, groups are a total mess.
芽生えた感動の再会 集まった愛称のWi-Fi
A touching reunion with Wi-Fi nicknames gathered.
交わった上等の忍耐 愛せるかが重なって
Intersecting endurance, overlapping our love—
狂った人類の状態 熱いミートパイみたいだね
Mad humanity looks like a hot meat pie!
パパパパパイ パイ! パイ!
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pie, pie, pie!
愛! 愛! 愛! ほれほれ 踊れ! 驚け! 尊い!
Love! Look and dance! Be amazed and precious!
甘酸っぱいレモンギュッバイ 人類いっぱい満杯DAY!
Lemon goodbye, humanity's packed-full day!
乾杯! 完全無欠にほれほれ 踊れ!
Cheers! Flawlessly look, look, and dance!
夜見る夢みたいね 愛のリアマドマンの中!
Like a dream inside the liar madman!
野良のロールも呼んでのパイか 祭典 乱舞しちゃいな今日も
A stray roll's pie? Dance wildly at this festival!
お代わり欲しいでしょ レンジでチンして脳みそまどろむの
You want seconds, right? Microwaved brains dozing off.
夜空の実現をスローガンに 精神をどうせパパパパパイ!
With the night sky as our slogan, crushing spirits anyway!
人類最高のダンスホール
Humanity's greatest dance hall!
ぼくらが生まれて初めて
The first time we were ever born,
知る音は心臓の鼓動だろう
the sound we knew was our heartbeat.
トントン トントン 天国と地獄
Thump thump, heaven and hell!
それはリズムと知った
We knew that as rhythm.
イニシエも 今ドキも イントロが包み詰まんでんだろう
Whether ancient or modern, intros wrap us up—
パパパパパイ パイ! パイ!
pa-pa-pa-pa-pie, pie, pie!
愛! 愛! 愛! ほれほれ 踊れ!
Love! Look, look, dance!
驚け! 尊い! 甘酸っぱいレモンギュッバイ
Be amazed! Precious lemon goodbye!
人類いっぱい満杯DAY! 乾杯!
Humanity's packed-full day! Cheers!
完全無欠にほれほれ 踊れ! 夜見る夢みたいね
Flawlessly dance like a night dream!
まるでバジルの上で踊ってみたい 生まれ変わったような気分です
Feeling as if reborn dancing on basil!
ラン! ファイイン! 人類分かって笑ってれ!
Run! Fine! Humanity understand and laugh!
寂しいのなんの 終わらないパイのように続けりゃいい
Lonely, but if we keep going like an endless pie,
健全なんてできないが お代わり欲しいでしょ
being wholesome is impossible, but you want seconds?
愛! 愛! 愛! ほれほれ 踊れ!
Love! Look, look, dance!
尊い! 甘酸っぱいレモンギュッバイ 人類いっぱい満杯だ!
Precious lemon goodbye, humanity's packed!
また一歩目削れ いつでもいいよ お代わり欲しいでしょ
Carving another step, you want seconds?
愛! 愛! 愛! ほれほれ 踊れ! 満杯DAY! 乾杯!
Love! Look, dance! Packed-full day! Cheers!
愛! 愛! 愛! 愛で、踊れダンスホール!
Love! Dance in the dance hall!
マジのセ・サー・メ・! 転がしていきました! ドンと! 上げました!
We rolled out the real Sesame! Boom, raised it!
はい、デュエット、どうでしたか?
Yes, how was the duet?
いい感じ! 最高だった! やばいね!
Feels great! It was the best! Amazing!
なんか雑な感じがエモかった。エモかったよね、もっちゃん。
The sloppy vibe felt emotional, right Mots-chan?
えもかったよね! えもかった! えもかった! イェーイ!
It was emotional! Emotional! Yay!
お前が一番適当だった。
You were the most casual.
そうそうそうそう。イェーイ! えもかったじゃん。
That's right! It was emotional, right?
はい、ということでね、告知タイムです!
So with that, it's announcement time!
まず、フレア、紹介お願いします。一つ目は、ステージジオラマアクリルスタンド!
First, the stage diorama acrylic stand!
Nardack先生に描き下ろしていただきました! 今回のライブをイメージしたステージ風のジオラマです。
Drawn by Nardack-sensei for this live!
4人分あるので並べても重ねても飾れます。ぜひ4人分集めて飾ってください!
Collect all four and display them!
次、ノエル! はーい!
Next is Noel! Hi!
二つ目は、法被! 大きくイラストが入っているので推しアピールに持ってこいです!
Second is the Happi coat with huge art!
え、4人それぞれ出るのですが、
Um, they'll all be released for the four of us,
一部はね、お揃いになっているので、こちらはですね、
but some items match, so these ones are...
箱推しの子もぜひぜひということで、かっこい、うん、静かにしろー！
Definitely for oshi-oshi fans too! So, cool— shh, quiet down!
かっこいいデザインなので、着るだけじゃなく飾っても最高のハピとなってます！ハッピーになりましょう！では次ぺこら！
It's such a cool design, so it'll be great not just to wear, but to display! Let's be happy! Next up, Pekora!
いやぺこらじゃないよ。はい、次はこちら！
No, I'm not Pekora! Next up is this!
ランダムスクエア缶バッジ！今回のライブテーマに合わせた、スクエアの缶バッジでーす！
Random square tin badges! These square tin badges match the theme of this live!
えーっとね、四角なので並べやすく、イラストはグッズ好きには嬉しすぎる！8種から2種類ずつの全8種類、ランダムでお届け！次のマリン！
Um, since they're square, they're easy to line up, and illustrations—super exciting for goods lovers! 8 types, 2 of each, total of 8 random types delivered! Next, Marine!
はい。普通これ背の順じゃないよ！ちょ、転げた！大丈夫？転げてますけど。
Yes. Wait, this isn't in height order! Whoa, I fell over! Are you okay? You fell over though.
ということで、こちら！
So, here it is!
スクエアポケットトートバッグです！
The square pocket tote bag!
え、これもですね、今回のライブをイメージして、前面にロゴなどがはいったスクエア型のポケットがついています！A4が入る大きさになっているので、使い勝手抜群です！
Um, this one is also inspired by our live concert, featuring a square pocket on the front with the logo and more! It's big enough to fit A4 size, so it's super practical!
はい、まだまだあるので紹介していきますね！次はこちら！
Yep, there's still more to introduce! Next is this!
はい、スクエアイヤーカフ！さりげなく推しアピールがしたい方にお勧め！
Yes, square ear cuffs! Recommended for those who want to subtly show their oshi support!
それぞれの名前や誕生日が入っているので、片耳ずつ別のものをつけてもいいし、両方つけてもいいし、使い方は自由です！
Since each has their name and birthday, you can wear different ones on each ear or both—how you use them is up to you!
実はね、キービジュアルで、先輩たちもつけているので、お揃いにしちゃって下さい！なんかマリン、なんかすごい！すごい力を持ってる。アシュラ！
Actually, in the key visual, the seniors are wearing them too, so please match with them! Marine looks kind of amazing! She has incredible power. Asura!
そして最後はこちら！ブロマイドケース！
And finally, here it is! The bromide case!
こちら、なんと！ご購入いただいた方にはキービジュアルのブロマイドと我々4人の手書きメッセージが書かれたメッセージもついてきます！あ、違う！手書きメッセージが書かれたカードもついてきます！カード！はい、メッセージの内容は届いてからのお楽しみです！こちら、ちょっとあのメッセージは複製なので、ご容赦下さい！
This, amazingly, comes with a key visual bromide and a message card featuring handwritten messages from all four of us! Oh wait, a card with handwritten messages! A card! Yes, the content of the message is a surprise until it arrives! This, well, the message is a replica, so please understand!
以上です！はい、今回はフルセット販売はないので、欲しいものをそれぞれ単品購入していただく形になります！
That's all! Yep, since there's no full set sale this time, you'll need to purchase each desired item individually!
数量限定もないので、皆さんよく吟味して選んでくださいね！
There's no limited quantity either, so please carefully consider and choose!
お願いしまーす！おねがいしまーす！ということで、マリンだくさんのグッズ紹介でした！詳細はグッズ販売ページなどからご確認ください！
Please do! Please do! So that was Marine's jam-packed goods introduction! Please check the goods sales page for details!
はい！ではこここも終わったところで、ライブはいよいよ終盤に入っております！改めて今までの5周年と今後6周年に向けて、一言ずつもらえればと思います！
Yes! Now that this is done, the live is entering its final stretch! I'd like to ask each of you to say a word looking back at the past 5 years and toward the upcoming 6th year!
じゃあ、喋りたい人、健康で、楽しく、ゆるいに、会社のルールを守って、怒られないように、せーのっ！
So, whoever wants to speak: stay healthy, have fun, take it easy, follow company rules, don't get yelled at, ready, set!
オタクたちが頑張ってしがみついてるみたいな、ファンタジー？
Like otaku trying hard to hold on—fantasy?
え、でも、最後のサビをよろしくお願いします！まだまだライブは続くので、お楽しみください！えーい！
Um, but please look forward to the final chorus! The live continues, so please enjoy! Yay!
お楽しみに！えい！へい！
Look forward to it! Hey! Hey!
あの日見わたした浅瀬を
I can still remember the shore we saw that day...
今も思い出すんだ
I'm thinking of it even now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words we carved in the sand, the sight of you walking ahead
寄り添う波が足元を よぎり何かをさらう
As the hugging waves brush our feet, taking something away
夕暮れの中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
In the twilight, only the evening passes by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks bloom in a flash of light
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely a never-ending summer
曖昧な心を溶かして繋いだ
Melted our uncertain hearts and tied them together
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あの日見渡した渚を今も思い出すんだ
I can still remember the shore we saw that day.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, the sight of your back.
寄り添う波が足元をよぎり何かをさらう
The clinging waves brush past my feet, sweeping something away.
夕凪の中日暮れだけが通り過ぎてゆく
In the evening calm, only twilight passes by.
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
Again and again, I put it into words and call to you.
波間を選びもう一度
Choosing the space between waves, once more.
もう二度と悲しまずに済むように
So that we never have to feel sad again...
パッと光って咲いた花火を見ていた
We watched fireworks blooming in a flash of light.
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
Surely they still lingered within our hearts.
手を伸ばせば触れたあったかい未来は
The warm future we could touch if we reached out
ひそかに二人を見ていた
Was quietly watching over the two of us.
パッと花火が
Fireworks in a flash
夜に咲いた
Bloomed in the night,
夜に咲いて
Blooming in the night,
静かに消えた
And quietly disappearing.
離さないで
Don't let go,
もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little longer, stay like this.
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out upon that day,
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand,
君の後ろ姿
The silhouette of your back.
パッと光って咲いた花火を見ていた
We watched fireworks blooming in a flash.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely a summer that will never end
曖昧な心を解いて繋いだ
Unraveled our uncertain hearts and tied them together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
次とその次とその次と線を引き続けた
I kept drawing lines to the next, and the next,
次の目的地を目的地を描くんだ宝島
Drawing the next destination, treasure island.
このまま君を連れて行くよ
I'll take you along just like this.
丁寧丁寧丁寧に描くよ
I will draw it carefully, ever so carefully.
揺れたり震えたりした線で丁寧丁寧丁寧に描いていたよ
With shaking, trembling lines, I drew it with care.
次もその次もその次もまだ目的地じゃない
The next and the next still aren't the destination.
夢の景色を景色を探すんだ宝島
Searching for the scenery of dreams, treasure island.
このまま君を連れて行くよ
I'll take you along just like this.
丁寧丁寧丁寧に歌うよ
I will sing it carefully, ever so carefully.
揺れたり震えたりしたって丁寧丁寧丁寧に歌うよ
Even if I shake and tremble, I'll sing with care.
それでも君を連れて行くよ
Even so, I will take you along with me.
揺れたり震えたりした線で描くよ君の歌
With shaking, trembling lines, I'll draw your song.
次も
Next,
その次も
and the next,
その次も まだ目的地じゃない
and the next still isn't our destination.
夢の 景色を
The scenery of dreams...
景色を探すんだ 宝島
searching for that scenery, Treasure Island.
このまま君を連れて行くよ
I'll take you along with me just like this,
丁寧に 丁寧に 丁寧に歌うと
singing carefully, carefully, carefully.
揺れたり震えたりしたりして
Swaying and trembling,
丁寧に 丁寧に 丁寧に歌うと 決めてたけど
singing carefully, carefully, carefully, though I had decided so—
このまま君を連れて行くよ
I'll take you along with me just like this,
丁寧に 丁寧に 丁寧に描くよ
drawing carefully, carefully, carefully.
揺れたり震えたりしたりして
Swaying and trembling,
丁寧に 丁寧に 丁寧に歌うよ
singing carefully, carefully, carefully.
それでも君を連れて行くよ
Even so, I'll take you along with me,
揺れたり震えたりした線で
with a line that swayed and trembled,
描くよ 君の歌を
I'll draw your song.